(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-16T00:18:11.304228",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あたしタランちゃま！クモ人間なの！
I'm Taran-chama! I'm a spider-person!
お前を食っちゃうぞ～！
I'm gonna eat you up!
うふふ！だめだよ～！
Ufufu! You can't do that!
ずっとみんな、なかよし！
We'll be friends forever!
うふ、やくそくだよ？
Hehe, it's a promise, okay?
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you somewhere beneath this same sky?
今まで私の心を埋めていたもの
The thing that had filled my heart until now...
失って初めて気がついた
...I only realized its value after losing it.
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
It had been supporting me so much...
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
...and giving me so many smiles.
失ってしまった代償は
The price of losing it...
とてつもなく大きすぎて
...is far too immense.
取り戻そうと必死に
As I desperately try to win it back,
手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
I stretch out my hand and struggle,
まるで風のようにすり抜けて
but it slips through like the wind,
届きそうで届かない
seeming so close, yet remaining out of reach.
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
With my chest tightened by loneliness and despair,
心が壊れそうになるけれど
my heart feels like it's about to break, but...
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
...your smile that remains in my memories...
私をいつも励ましいてくれる
...always gives me encouragement.
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's return to those days once again.
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time, it will surely be alright.
いつもそばで笑っていよう
Let's always be smiling by each other's side,
あなたのすぐそばで...
right beside you...
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, and what are you doing?
この空の...
Beneath this sky...
...の続く場所にいますか
Are you in the place where it continues...?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか
Are you smiling, just like always?
今はまだそれを願い続ける
Even now, I keep wishing for that.
生誕ライブ限定 グッズ販売のお知らせ！
Birthday Live Exclusive Merch Announcement!
家族写真B2タペストリー
Family Photo B2 Tapestry!
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと...
With a gorgeous frame-like design...
肖像画のような二人が...
...and the two of them looking like portraits...
とってもキュート
...they are so cute!
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って...
Decorate your room's wall with today's memories...
彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます！
...and enjoy a colorful life of supporting your favorite!
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ
Outing-Chama Plushie!
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ！
A plushie with very cute button-like eyes!
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと...
Chama in her dress outfit, meticulously reproduced piece by piece...
一緒におでかけして旅に出れちゃいます！
You can go out and go on a journey together!
鞄に付けれるハートチャーム付き！
Comes with a heart charm to attach to your bag!
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch!
あの... タランちゃまが！ポーチに？！
That... Taran-Chama! Is a pouch?!
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム！
A convenient item with a zipper on the back that opens for storage!
ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが、可愛すぎる！
Taran-Chama in her gothic lolita outfit is just too cute!
チェーンがついてるから、安心してお外にお散歩させられるよ！
With the attached chain, you can safely take her out for a walk!
タランちゃまスマホリング
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring!
スマホの落下は、タランちゃまにお任せ！
Leave preventing smartphone drops to Taran-Chama!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます！
She will stick tightly and protect it!
愛くるしいお目目と、つい目が合っちゃう瞬間も...
Even those moments when you lock eyes with her adorable eyes...
癒されてたまりません！
...are irresistibly soothing!
全部セットは数量限定もあります！
The full set is also available in limited quantities!
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは...
The limited edition version of the full set purchase bonus includes...
箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと...
...a postcard with a foil-stamped duplicated message...
赤井はあと直筆サイン
...and Akai Haato's handwritten signature!
特典ボイス『ひみつの話』もあるよ！
There's also a bonus voice track, 'Secret Talk'!
プロモカードもあるよ！
A promo card is included too!
hololive公式ECサイトへGO！
Go to the official hololive EC site!
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ見つけたものは
The only thing, the one and only thing I found...
誠実で不器用な、それでも柔らかな声
...was a sincere, clumsy, yet gentle voice.
朽ちてゆき、ただ崩れゆく、世界を照らす
Illuminating a world that is decaying and simply crumbling away,
暖かで、でも残酷な、去り際の笑顔
a warm, yet cruel, parting smile.
ひび割れてく翡翠の水槽を満たすもの
Filling the cracking jade aquarium.
「永遠ではない」なんて、初めから解ってたのに
Even though I knew from the start that 'nothing is forever'...
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
What carves into my heart, remaining beautiful even when broken,
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとりひとりの記憶
are the memories of each person, beautiful even when shattered.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
What remains in my heart, so agonizingly even though I want to forget,
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
is that faint sensation that made me forget even the pain.
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ伝えたのは
The only thing, the one and only thing I conveyed,
冷たさで誤魔化した、苦し紛れの嘘
was a desperate lie disguised with coldness.
愛しくて、ただ愛しくて、選んだ言葉は
The words I chose, out of pure, deep love,
すべて終わらせる偽りのセリフ
were a false line to bring everything to an end.
風が吹けば飛ぶような砂に残した手紙
A letter left in the sand, likely to blow away with a gust of wind.
「永遠ではない」という...
That 'nothing is forever'...
「永遠ではない」ということさえ忘れられたのに…
Even though I'd forgotten that "nothing lasts forever"...
もう一度、もう一度と、もう何度思ったでしょう
How many times have I thought, "Just once more, just once more"?
枯れた花束、捨てられもせず
Holding a withered bouquet, unable to even throw it away,
降り止まぬ雨は、まるで万雷の拍手喝采
The unending rain is like a thunderous round of applause,
愚かな後悔を 嘲笑う怒涛のよう
Like a surging wave laughing at my foolish regrets.
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
Even if it's broken, what still beautifully carves into my chest...
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとひらの記憶
Even if it's shattered, is a single beautiful petal of memory.
ああ忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
Oh, though I want to forget, what maddeningly remains in my heart...
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
Is that faint touch that made me forget even the pain.
痛みさえ忘れさせた、
It made me forget even the pain...
微かな感触
A faint touch.
「なんでいなくなっちゃうの…」
"Why are you leaving me...?"
「こんなの苦しいよ…」
"This hurts so much..."
「そばにいて…」
"Stay by my side..."
「いつも、そばにいるよ。」
"I will always be by your side."
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've completely forgotten
夏の木陰に座ったまま
how we sat in the shade of the summer trees,
アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
tossing ice cream into our mouths and waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've completely forgotten
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
how we said the whole world is full of lies,
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
and laughed about going to find its true value together?
忘れないように
So that we won't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it won't fade away,
形に残るものが全⾮じゃないように
so that tangible things won't be everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
tell me that summer is coming.
僕が描いてる目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
What was reflected in the eyes I drew was a ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて
With my skirt swaying in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
forgetting all about memories,
浅い呼吸をする
I take shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away the sweat, summer begins to bloom.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've completely forgotten
夏の木陰に座った頃
the time when we sat in the shade of the summer trees,
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
and how a cloud peeked out from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You reached out to grab it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
with your hand foolishly slicing through the empty air,
僕は紙に雲一つを書いて
while I drew a single cloud on a piece of paper,
笑って握って見せて
showing it to you with a smile in my hand.
忘れないように
So that we won't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it won't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
because what remains in history isn't everything.
今だけ顔も失くして
For now, let's even lose our faces,
言葉も全部忘れて
and completely forget our words.
君は笑ってる
You are smiling,
夏を待っている
waiting for summer.
僕らは亡霊だ
We are ghosts...
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more of your heart...
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me the summer scent...
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So I won't forget...
色褪せないように
So it won't fade...
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because what echoes in the heart isn't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words...
さよならだって教えて
Tell me how to say goodbye, too.
今も見るんだよ 夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
Even now I see it, the ghost in the summer-blooming flower.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time.
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but your heart.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths...
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, becoming like summer.
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten...
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the shade of a summer tree,
氷菓を口に放り込んで風を待っていた
popping ice pops into our mouths, waiting for the breeze.
というわけで、赤井はあと爆誕祭2025！
And with that, Akai Haato Birthday Festival 2025...
始まっちゃうよー！
...is starting!
イェーイ！
Yay!
お、事故！事故！事故！あー
Oh, crash! Crash! Crash! Ah!
あ、危ない、危ない
Ah, danger, danger!
一曲目、一曲目だから！
It's only the first song, the first song!
まだ、体力温存しないと
We still need to save our strength!
ということで、ゲストに来てくれたのは
And so, the guest who came to join us is...
らでんちゃん！
Raden-chan!
こんばんは！ホロライブDEV_IS、ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございます！
Good evening! I am Juufuutei Raden from hololive DEV_IS, ReGLOSS!
ありがとう、来てくれて！
Thank you for coming!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして、新衣装じゃないですか！
And, isn't that a new outfit!
そうなんです！タララララン
That's right! Ta-da-da-da!
綺麗！かわいい！
Beautiful! Cute!
イェーイ！
Yay!
この衣装めっちゃシナジーある！
These outfits have so much synergy!
あ、あ、あ、あれ？
Ah, ah, ah, what?
なんか、らでんちゃん言ってたけど、これ、クリスマスカラーだね、二人で
Actually, Raden-chan was saying earlier, this makes a Christmas color scheme for the two of us!
そうなの！
Indeed!
イェーイ！
Yay!
らでんが今クリスマスツリー
I'm the Christmas tree now,
で、はあちゃまはサンタ
and Haachama is Santa!
サンタです
I'm Santa.
サンタ、この季節にぴったり...ん？
Santa! Perfectly matches this season... wait?
お、ぴったりですね、夏の匂いがします
Oh, perfect! It smells like summer!
全然関係ない！
Absolutely unrelated!
クリスマスだと思ってたのに！
And here I thought it was Christmas!
そっか、あと、はあちゃま、あ、はあちゃまじゃない、赤井はあと
Right! Also, Haachama... wait, not Haachama, Akai Haato...
爆誕祭2025でね
Birthday Festival 2025!
是非ともSNSでスクショとか呟いてください！
Please post screenshots and tweets on SNS!
来てください！お願いします！
Please do! We beg you!
じゃあ、なんか写真撮るか！
Then, let's take some photos!
写真撮りましょう！しとやかなポーズで行きますか？
Let's take photos! Should we go with a graceful pose?
せっかくなので、シャキーン！
Since we're here... Sha-keen!
どすこい！
Dosukoi!
どすこい？
Dosukoi?
キメポーズ！しとやかなポーズ！
Signature pose! A graceful pose!
あ、これいいんじゃない？ホロライブ！
Ah, isn't this good? Hololive!
強そう！強そう！強そう！
Looks strong! Looks strong! Looks strong!
えー、じゃあ、どうしようかな、あ、ちょっとハートで！
Well, what should we do next... Oh, how about a heart?
今時のハート！ハートで！
A trendy heart! With a heart!
いいんじゃないですか！あ、可愛い！イェーイ！
Isn't this great? Oh, cute! Yay!
そして、空間そして、そして、ハート！
And, and, and, heart!
きゃー！あははは
Kyah! Ahahaha!
戻ってきて、戻ってきて！
Come back, come back!
もう、うちらの中じゃないですか！
We're basically soul sisters, aren't we?
うわー、危ない、危ない
Whoa, dangerous, dangerous!
今のね、着物のコツ入れただけだから
I was just adjusting my kimono's fit just now.
コツ入れられたんですか？
Did you adjust it?
まずい、まずい、戻りましょう、落っこちたりとかしないからね、別に
Uh oh, let's head back. It's not like we're going to fall or anything.
しっとりした曲歌った後ですからね、そうだよ、しとやかね保存版
This is right after we sang a quiet song, after all! That's right, we must be graceful.
しとやかにね
Gracefully.
みんなスクショ撮ってくれてるかな？
I wonder if everyone is taking screenshots?
撮ってくれてるかな？
Are they taking screenshots?
というわけで、今回ですね、我々は
And so, this time, we are...
なんか、ホロライブ...
Like, hololive...
そうですよ、我々のユニット名、ホロライブですからね、覚えてくださいね
That's right, our unit name is 'hololive', so please remember it!
いつの間にできてたの？だいぶ前？
When was that made? A long time ago?
そうそう、ホロライブって感じで、らでんちゃんに来てもらいました！
Right, right! Under the 'hololive' banner, we had Raden-chan join us!
そうですね、あの、衣装もシナジーがあるということで
Indeed. Our outfits have synergy too.
え、花に亡霊をね、歌ったんですけども、どうでした？
So, we sang "Ghost in a Flower," how was it?
え、もう…エモ。
It was just... emo.
いや、エモ。
No, really, emo.
いや、このステージとすっごい合ってたし。
Yeah, it really matched this stage perfectly.
いや、やっぱね、あのラベンちゃんに歌ってほしいパートがあったんですよ、やっぱ。
And you know, there was a part I really wanted Raven-chan to sing.
え？ / どこどこ？
Eh? / Where, where?
「歴史に残るものだけがすべてじゃない」ってところで
At the part, "Not only things that remain in history are everything..."
あ、これちょっとラベンちゃんに歌ってほしいなと思って
I thought, "Ah, I really want Raven-chan to sing this!"
そのパートを分けさせてもらいました！
So I assigned that part to you!
嬉しい！ / はーい！
I'm so happy! / Yay!
でも、どっかで歌いたいなって思ってた曲だったから
But it was a song I've been wanting to sing somewhere,
あ、そうなんだ！よかった〜！ / この曲一緒に歌いたいんだって言ってくれた時
Oh, really? I'm so glad! / ...so when you said you wanted to sing it together,
「え、めっちゃ嬉しい！」と思って。 / よかった、嬉しい！
I was like, "Wow, I'm so happy!" / I'm glad, so happy!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
じゃあ、じゃあ頑張って帰ってね。
Well then, do your best to go back.
こ、ここから？！ここ…ここから？！ええ？！
Fr-from here?! From... from here?! What?!
あははは！うん。もう、じゃ、じゃあね、ほな！
Hahaha! Yeah. Well, see ya, bye!
ほな！
Bye!
これからも頑張ってください！
Please keep doing your best!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
これからも頑張ってください…これどうやって帰るの？
Please keep doing your best... How do I go back?
これどうやって帰るの？
How do I go back?
あ、あっち、あっち、こっち、あっち。
Ah, over there, over there, here, there.
そう、あっちとかこっちとかあるんだ、こういうのって。あ、木、危ない。
Right, there's "over there" and "over here" for these things. Ah, the tree, watch out!
ありがとう！頑張ってください！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Good luck! Bye-bye!
あーあー
Ah...
らららら…
La la la...
遥か遠い遠い昔に巻かれた首輪
A collar wound tight around my neck a long, long time ago
人が欲しい 人が欲しいと
I want people, I want people...
叫ぶ呪いの首輪
...screams the cursed collar.
怒らないで 見捨てないで
Don't be angry, don't abandon me...
どこも行かないで
...don't go anywhere.
強く締める 吐くまで締める
Squeezing tightly, squeezing till I vomit...
人がいない いないと
...crying out that there's nobody, nobody.
いい成績でしょう ねえ ねえ
I have great grades, right? Hey, hey.
いい子でしょう
I'm a good child, right?
かわいい子でしょう ねえ
I'm a cute child, right? Hey,
良い子でしょう
I'm a good child, right?
苦しい ねえ
It hurts, hey.
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
もっと もっと
more and more.
愛して 愛して
Love me, love me,
狂おしいほどに
to the point of madness.
苦しい 苦しい
It hurts, it hurts,
呪縛を 解いて 解いて ねえ
break this curse, break it, hey.
止められない
It cannot be stopped...
ああ
...ah.
あーあー
Ah...
体 体 大きくなっても
Even as my body, my body grows...
小さい首輪
...the collar remains small.
苦しくなる 足りなくなる
It becomes painful, it becomes insufficient...
人が 人が 足りない
...there are not enough, not enough people.
クラスの誰にも負けない
I'm better than anyone in my class,
綺麗ないい子でしょう
a beautiful, good child, right?
誰よりも 誰よりも
More than anyone, more than anyone,
誰も彼も 私を見てよ
everyone, look at me.
体育館裏
Behind the gymnasium...
あなたに 告白を
...I confess my love to you.
嘘みたいでしょう
It seems like a lie, doesn't it?
あなたが好きなの
I like you,
汚いあなたを
even your dirty self.
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
全部あげる
I'll give you everything.
あなたに あなたに
To you, to you,
全部背負ってもらうよ
I'll make you bear everything.
足りない あなたが
It's not enough, you...
足りない 離さないよ
...are not enough. I won't let go.
ああ
Ah...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
もっと もっと
more and more.
愛して 愛して
Love me, love me,
狂おしいほどに
to the point of madness.
苦しい 離さない
It hurts, I won't let go,
苦しい もっともっと ねえ
it hurts, more and more, hey.
幸せなの
I'm happy...
ああ
...ah.
おおー！
Oh...!
幸せなの？
Are you happy?
Yay!
Yeah!
We got chainsaws!
I got one! Me too!
I want one too!
Haachama's chainsaw too!
I want to chase that too!
Oh wow, that's heavy.
Okay, let's fight.
Let's go!
Yeah!
I feel so 努力、未来、A BEAUTIFUL STAR!
I feel so effort, future, a beautiful star!
Yeah, innocent! I wanna ride the chainsaw!
努力、未来、A BEAUTIFUL STAR!
Effort, future, a beautiful star!
愛して
Love me
愛して、愛して、愛して was so nice!
"Love me, love me, love me" was so nice!
Yeah, we sang together.
Happy birthday, Haachama!
Yay, it's a really nice birthday today!
Thank you for letting us celebrate with you.
Thanks for playing!
That was so fun!
Oh, it's the first time we also with the... blue?
Yeah!
And... Haachama... we are...
Hachatorisa! We made it!
We just jumbled our names together.
Let's take a picture!
Okay, everyone take a picture.
Nice!
Yeah! Take a screenshot!
It's so cool!
Dangerous! Dangerous!
Let's kill them!
On camera?
Yeah, camera!
Say goodbye!
Goodbye!
ねえ 私 知ってるよ 君が ひとり
Hey, I know you're all alone.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
ピコピコ 震えてさ
Beeping and shaking.
子供だもの 無理なんじゃない？
You're just a kid, so isn't it impossible?
正直に言っちゃいよ
Just say it honestly.
バレてるんだし 言っちゃいよ
It's already exposed, so just say it.
聞いてんの？
Are you listening?
フツフツ 恥ずかしい
Seething and embarrassed.
みんな隠しているだけ
They're all just hiding it.
モニタリング
[Title: Monitoring]
ねえ 私 知ってるよ 君が ひとり 涙し
Hey, I know you shed tears alone.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
ズクンズクン 凹んでさ
Throbbing and feeling down.
弱い人から いいんじゃない？
Why not start with the weak?
朝が来るまで 一生仮想 もっと泣いたって
Until morning comes, let's imagine forever, even if you cry more...
何度だって 受け止めてあげる
No matter how many times, I will accept you.
もう不安はナシにして
Put your anxieties aside,
いっぱい出していってね
and let it all out.
ほら おねがい 君が欲しいの
Look, please, I want you.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク
Let me comfort you, shake shake.
愛のサインで 泣いてくれるかな
Will you cry for me at the sign of love?
濡れていてよ 体痛い？
Stay wet, does your body hurt?
ねえ いいでしょ
Hey, it's fine, right?
喉元通って飲み干したい
I want to drink it down through my throat.
だ、だ、だ、だ、だ
Da, da, da, da, da!
ほら おねがい 君が欲しいの
Look, please, I want you.
手料理散らして シックラブ
Scattering home-cooked meals, sick love.
なんて最高ね 分けてくれるかな
How wonderful, will you share it with me?
君の痛い？ 見せてよ
Does it hurt? Show me.
ねえ いいでしょ
Hey, it's fine, right?
吸い取って 吸い取りたい
I want to suck it up, absorb it.
だ、だ、だ、だ、だ
Da, da, da, da, da!
みたい みたい みたい...
Want to see, want to see, want to see...
君の中
Inside you.
みたい みたい みたい...
Want to see, want to see, want to see...
ねえ 私 知ってるよ 君が ひとり 悔しがってるの
Hey, I know you're frustrated all alone.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
ズクンズクン 固まっちゃう
Throbbing and freezing up.
君を推すことをやめない
I won't stop supporting you.
ねえ 私 知ってるよ 君はできる子
Hey, I know you can do it.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
辛い日々は 弱い子ならでは ちょうどいい
Painful days are just right for weak kids.
私それでも好きだよ
I still love you despite that.
ほら おねがい 君が欲しいの
Look, please, I want you.
名前を呼んでよ いっちょ
Call my name for once.
いつだって愛の参上 君はひとりだ
Love arrives anytime, you are all alone.
だから歌う ひとりじゃない
So I sing, you are not alone.
ねえ いいでしょ
Hey, it's fine, right?
そのプレイは おしまいな
That play is over.
だ、だ、だ、だ、だ
Da, da, da, da, da!
君がやめる時も
Even when you stop,
私 側にいるわ
I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'll always be watching over you.
さあもう怖くないのよ
See, it's not scary anymore.
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
慰めさせて シェイク
Let me comfort you, shake...
愛の才能で
...with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me...
枯れてしまう
...I will wither away.
濡れていたいの いいでしょ？
I want to be wet, is that okay?
舐めとって 飲み干したい
I want to lick you up and drink you dry.
吸いとって 吸いたい
Suck it out, I want to suck you in.
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you.
手を切り出して シェイク
Cut off your hand, shake...
ラブなんて最高ね
...love is the absolute best!
狂わせておくれなきゃ
If you don't drive me crazy...
君の痛み 感じてたい
...I want to feel your pain.
のぞいてたい
I want to peek inside...
吸いとって 吸いたい
...suck it out, I want to suck you in.
ねえ私 知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
ズルズル吸い込んで最後の1人からいいじゃない
Slurping and sucking it in, isn't starting with the last person fine?
朝が来るまで 一緒に遊ぼう まいったって
Let's play together until morning, even if you surrender.
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you over and over again.
わがままを言わないで だしてだしてだして
Don't be selfish, let me out, let me out, let me out!
ダン ダンダン...
Dan dan dan...
諦めの悪い輩
You stubborn bastards...
あんたらなんかじゃ束なっても敵わん
...you guys are no match even if you band together.
くわばらくわばらくわばら目にも止まらん早さ
Knock on wood, knock on wood... at blinding speed!
くたばらん黙らん下がらん押し通す我儘
I won't die, won't be silent, won't back down, pushing through my selfishness.
そこどきな邪魔だ 俺はもう1人のあなた
Out of my way, you're in the way! I am another you.
貞ちゃん伽椰ちゃんワンサカ黄泉の国wonderland
Sada-chan, Kaya-chan, a crowd in the underworld wonderland!
御祈祷中に何だが4時44分まわったら
Sorry to interrupt your prayers, but once it passes 4:44...
四尺四寸四分様がカミナッチャbang around
...the Four-Feet-Four-Inches-Four-Minutes ghost is coming to bang around!
呼ぶ声がしたんなら文字通りお憑かれさまやん
If you heard a voice calling, you're literally being possessed!
ハイレタハイレタハイレタハイレタハイレタ
I'm in, I'm in, I'm in, I'm in, I'm in!
必死で這い出た先で霧は晴れた
After desperately crawling out, the fog cleared.
凸と凹が
When the puzzle pieces...
噛み合ったら 痛みが重なったら
...fit together, and the pain overlaps...
心 身体 頭 滾ってゆく何か
...something starts to boil within my heart, body, and head.
背中に今 羽が 生えたならば
If wings were to sprout on my back right now...
暗闇からさらば
...farewell to the darkness!
飛び立っていく彼方
I'll fly away into the distance.
心 身体 頭 懐かしい温か
Heart, body, head, a nostalgic warmth...
足元に今 花が咲いたならば
...if flowers were to bloom at my feet right now...
暗闇からさらば
...farewell to the darkness!
飛び立っていく彼方
I'll fly away into the distance.
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
I will live on forever inside of you.
またの迷宮 耳の中
Back into the labyrinth inside your ears.
胸の奥に居続けてる メロディ リスニー
The melody that stays deep in your chest, listen to me.
ダン ダンダン...
Dan dan dan...
今日も生温い体と満たされない
Today again, with this lukewarm body, I'm unsatisfied...
積み上げてく トップ トップ
...stacking it up, top, top!
鬼とチャンポンで デリケートなジェサマサッカー
Mixing with demons, a delicate master soccer match.
渡ろう海原 鼻歌交じり シャララ
Let's cross the ocean humming a song, sha-la-la.
祓いたいなら待って待ってサババ
If you want to exorcise it, wait, wait, sababa!
誰が開いたかパンドラ後者は何があっても知らんがな
Who opened Pandora? I don't care what happens to whoever comes after!
何百年経って調子久しぶりのシャバだ
After hundreds of years, I'm back in the free world!
学ラン若者丸太構築じゃねえよ馬鹿が
It's not a school uniform log construction, you idiots!
今確実に目が合ったな
Our eyes definitely just met.
こういうことかよシャマラ
So this is how it is, shamara!
ハイレタハイレタハイレタハイレタハイレタ
I'm in, I'm in, I'm in, I'm in, I'm in!
眠り飽きた先で君が待ってた
After waking up from sleep, you were waiting.
縦と横が
When either length or width...
片方欠けたら 怒りが消え去ったら
...is missing, and the anger is gone...
心 身体 頭 滾ってゆく何か
...something starts to boil within my heart, body, and head.
背中に今 羽が 生えたならば
If wings were to sprout on my back right now...
暗闇からさらば
...farewell to the darkness!
飛び立っていく彼方
I'll fly away into the distance.
心 身体 頭 懐かしい温か
Heart, body, head, a nostalgic warmth...
足元に今 花が咲いたならば
...if flowers were to bloom at my feet right now...
暗闇からさらば
...farewell to the darkness!
飛び立っていく彼方
I'll fly away into the distance.
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
I will live on forever inside of you.
またの迷宮 耳の中
Back into the labyrinth inside your ears.
私が前から会いたかった方の ご自宅ということなんですが
This is the home of someone I have wanted to meet for a long time, but...
なにやらとんでもない雰囲気が 漂ってます
...there is a really eerie vibe in the air.
この階段の先に...
At the top of these stairs...
オカルト界隈でも有名な 呪物コレクターの方がいるはずなので
...there should be a cursed item collector who is famous in the occult world, so...
早速突撃してみたいと思います！
...I'm going to go pay them a surprise visit!
行きましょう！
Let's go!
ドキドキ...
I'm so nervous...
結構階段の段差が...
These stairs are quite steep...
うおぉ...
Whoa...
めっちゃ暗い！
It's so dark!
一番奥のお部屋のはずなので 先に進んで行きましょう
Their room should be at the very end, so let's head on inside.
なんかスゴイ、異質ですね
This is amazing. It feels so out of the ordinary.
じゃあ、ここの、あ、この部屋なんですね保存
Oh, so it's this room right here.
この一番奥のお部屋のはずなので
This should be the room at the very end.
ちょっと表札もないですが 一応ノックしてみますか？
There's no nameplate, but should we try knocking anyway?
トントン
*knocks*
あれ、ここで合ってますかね？ もう一度ノックしてみますか？
Wait, is this the right place? Should I knock again?
はい
Yes?
声が...
I heard a voice...
あ...
Oh...
どうも
Hello.
あ、どうも。あの、田中さんですか？
Ah, hello. Are you Mr. Tanaka?
はい
Yes.
ホロライブ1期生の 赤井はあとと申します
I'm Akai Haato from Hololive Gen 1.
インタビュー撮影に来たんですが もし良かったら撮影...
I'm here for an interview, and if it's okay, could we film...?
大丈夫ですか？
Is that alright?
大丈夫ですよ
That's fine.
あ、ホントですか？
Oh, really?
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
ありましたっけ？ そういうの約束してましたっけ？
Wait, did we? Did we make an appointment for that?
すいません
I'm sorry.
忘れてました？
Did you forget?
ちょっと忘れてましたね
Yes, I had completely forgotten about it.
でもなんかもうすでに色々見えてますけども 入ってもいいですか？
I can already see all kinds of things here, but may I come in?
はい、どうぞ
Yes, please come in.
はい、おねがいします保存
Thank you!
お邪魔します。失礼します
Excuse me. Thank you for having me.
これ全部呪物なんですか？
Are all of these cursed objects?
そうなんですよね。あの、呪物というか、 まあ、呪われた...
Yes, they are. Well, rather than just cursed objects, they are... cursed...
呪われた... 呪われちゃってるんだ
Cursed... They're actually cursed.
え、田中さんは大丈夫なんですか？
Wait, are you okay being around them, Mr. Tanaka?
いや、でもずっとしんどいですよ
No, to be honest, I feel unwell all the time.
えぇ！？
What?!
え、もう全部ちゃんと呪われている...？
Wait, so every single one of them is actually cursed...?
そうですね。中にはまあ、 あの、良い物もありますけど
Yes. Well, some of them are actually good items, though.
あ、そうなんですね。なんか呪いにも ちょっと種類があるんですか？
Oh, I see. So there are different types of curses?
ありますね
Yes, there are.
ちなみに、今配信を見ている人たちのために 田中さんがどんな方なのか自己紹介してもらっても
By the way, for the viewers watching this stream, could you introduce yourself and tell us what you do?
よろしいですか？
Would that be okay?
ええ
Sure.
呪物コレクターの田中俊行です。 よろしくお願いします
I'm Toshiyuki Tanaka, a cursed object collector. Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you too!
仕事は怪談師なんですよ。 怖い話の
My actual job is a ghost story teller, telling scary stories.
えー、そうなんだ
Oh, really?
趣味、ライフワークで 呪われたものを集めてる
Collecting cursed items is my hobby and lifework.
趣味なんだ...
It's a hobby?!
じゃあちなみに、今田中さんが立っている 奥の部屋にももう、呪物があるんですか？
So by the way, are there cursed objects in the back room where you are standing too?
そうなんですよ。元々こっちだけが 呪物部屋だったんですけど
Yes. Originally, only this room here was the cursed object room.
あ、そうなんですね、うん
Oh, I see. Yes.
量が入りきらなくなって
But I ran out of space as they piled up...
はい、あ、奥にも。 入れたりするんですか？
Ah, so there are some in the back too. Can we go inside?
奥入れますけど、奥は比較的 一番僕が個人契約してる呪物が多いので
You can, but that room has mostly cursed items that I have made personal pacts with.
へえ〜！
Wow!
入らない方がいい。入ったら危ない...
It's better not to go in. It's dangerous...
危ない...
Dangerous...
うん、あんましたぶん 呪物嫌がると思います
Yeah. I think the cursed objects would really dislike it.
あー、そんな感じなんだ
Ah, I see. It's like that.
なんか一番最初にここ入って、一番気になったのが あそこの、赤いお面の横にある白いお面で
When I first stepped in, the thing that caught my eye the most was that white mask next to the red one.
あれはどういう呪物なんですか？
What kind of cursed object is that?
あれは呪いの面って言われてて
That is called the "Cursed Mask"...
呪いの面...
Cursed Mask...
こう、つけたら不幸が 訪れるって言われてるんですよ
...and it's said that if you wear it, misfortune will befall you.
あ、そう、え、実際に何かそういうふうに 不幸が起こっちゃった人もいるんですか？
Really? Has anyone actually suffered misfortune because of it?
います。京都の蓮久寺っていうお寺、 そこに三木大雲さんっていう和尚がいる
Yes. In Kyoto, there is a temple called Renkyu-ji, and the head priest there is Master Daiun Miki.
はい、うんうん
Yes.
その三木大雲さんから預かったもので保存
This is something I'm holding on to on his behalf.
へえ〜
Wow.
多分これ、ピー（自主規制音）だと思いますけど、 [自主規制]と[自主規制]がつけたっていうんですよ
This will probably be bleeped out, but they say [Bleep] and [Bleep] actually wore it.
え、つけたの！？
Wait, they wore it?!
え、なんでつけちゃったんですか？
Why on earth did they put it on?
そういう番組があった。 試しにつけちゃえみたいなノリで
There was a TV show, and they wore it on a whim, like, "Let's try it on."
がっつり呪われちゃいましたね...
And they got heavily cursed...
そうですね
Yes, indeed.
ちゃんと呪われてるぅ...
They actually got cursed...
基本お祓いが済んでない物が、 ここでは普通です
Generally, items that haven't been purified are the norm here.
あー、だから僕もそういう呪物受け取る時に、 人を呪った物とかありますけど
So when I receive these cursed items, some of which were used to curse people...
その、お祓いはやめてくれって言います
...I tell them, "Please don't purify it."
珍しい
Haha, that's so unusual!
意味がなくなるので
Because otherwise, it loses its meaning.
え、じゃあちなみに、田中さんおすすめの、 あの、呪物ありますか？
Well, by the way, do you have a cursed item that you highly recommend?
あります、あります保存
Yes, I do.
おー
Oh!
じゃあちょっと持ってきますわ
Let me go get it for you.
持ってきてくれるんですね、おねがいしま〜す！
You're going to bring it! Yes, please!
あ、お人形さんだ！お人形さん持ってきてくれた
Oh, it's a doll! He brought a doll.
あ、奥の部屋...奥の部屋あれですよね？ 契約の部屋ですけど、大丈夫なんですか？
Wait, that room... that's the "Pact Room", right? Is it okay to go in?
危険な...危険なって w
Isn't it dangerous? She says it's dangerous, haha.
出せっていうから...
Well, she told me to bring her out...
あはは、ちょっと待って w保存
Haha, wait a minute!
あ、でも可愛い、可愛いなんか。パジャマ着てる
Oh, but she's cute! She's actually kind of cute. She's wearing pajamas.
可愛くない？ジェラピケ着てるんですよ
Isn't she cute? She's wearing Gelato Pique.
え、ジェラピケじゃない、あ、やっぱジェラピケなんだ！
Wait, really? It really is Gelato Pique!
なんでお気に入りなんですか？
Why is she your favorite?
あの、こう呪物を集める...
Well, when collecting cursed items...
おお、集めるきっかけになった人形。
Oh, so this is the doll that started your collection?
どういうきっかけで？
How did that happen?
元々怪談ライブとかやってたら お客さんが、あの、持ってくるんですよね。相談...
I originally did live scary story shows, and members of the audience started bringing them in...
えええ...ｗ
What...?
お祓いとかも出来ると思われてて
They thought I could perform exorcisms on them.
ちなみにお名前はなんて？
By the way, what is her name?
チャーミーっていう...
They call her Charmy.
あ、チャーミーさん。
Ah, Charmy-san.
関西の、あの、ある介護施設にいたんですよ。
She used to be at a nursing home in the Kansai region.
へえ、そうなんですね。
Oh, really?
で、こう、誰が持って来たか、スタッフの人も分からない。
And the staff had no idea who brought her there.
えええ...
What?
利用者の方が、特定の利用者の方が可愛がるんですよね、なぜか。
But for some reason, specific residents would become very fond of her.
え、あ、へえ。
Oh, wow.
可愛がると、三日以内に死ぬんです。
Once they grew fond of her, they would die within three days.
えっ...
What...?
それが五人続いたんで、
That happened to five people in a row,
五人も続いたんですね...
Five people in a row...
五人続いたんです。
Yes, five people.
なので、一度、地下の倉庫に隠したんですよね。
So they ended up hiding her in the basement storage.
隠されちゃったんだ。
They hid her away.
でも、次の日には出てきてた...
But the next day, she was back out again.
ちゃんと脱出してる...ｗ
She successfully escaped...
スタッフの人が僕のこと知ってて、
A staff member who knew about me...
「田中さんに預けよう」ということで、持って来てくれたんです。
decided to entrust her to me, so they brought her over.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
で、バタバタしてたんで、僕そのまま中身見ずに家に帰った。
I was busy at the time, so I went home without looking inside the box.
はい。
Yes.
家に帰ったら...
When I got home...
あの、部屋の明かりが、激しく明滅する...
the room lights started flickering violently.
ｗｗｗ
(giggles)
パソコン... PC立ち上げて、メールの返信しようと思っても、
I turned on my PC to reply to emails...
音声認識ソフトが立ち上がって、他のアプリが開けないんです。
but the voice recognition software kept opening, and I couldn't open any other apps.
で、なんか気になって、その、袋を開けたら、
I got a bit suspicious, and when I opened the bag...
この子が出てきた。
she came out.
その瞬間に、現象が一気に止んだ。
At that exact moment, the flickering and glitches completely stopped.
じゃあもう、「早く出してくれ」っていうやつだったんですかね。
So she was basically demanding to be let out?
なんかメッセージをたぶん... もしかしたら。
Maybe she was sending some kind of message.
でも、めっちゃ可愛い服まで着せて可愛がってますけど、生きてますね、田中さんは。
But you put her in such cute clothes and pamper her. Yet, you're still alive, Tanaka-san.
僕は、だから...
Well, actually...
この場では仲良いふりしてますけど、全然...
I'm just pretending to be close to her right now. In reality, I don't...
可愛がってない？
You don't pamper her?
可愛がってないというか、敬ってます。
I wouldn't say I don't pamper her, but I show her respect.
そこから、ちょっと物に霊的な物とか魂みたいな物が宿るんじゃないかなって思いだして、
That was when I started thinking that spirits or souls might reside in physical objects.
じゃあ起きたときは怖くなかったんですか？
Weren't you scared when those things started happening?
いや、めちゃくちゃ怖いです。
Oh, I was absolutely terrified.
あ、ちゃんと怖かったんだ！
Ah, so you actually were scared!
そういうの、怖くないタイプなのかと思ってました。
I thought you were the type who doesn't get scared of things like that.
めちゃくちゃ怖いです。
I get absolutely terrified.
次ちょっと...
Next...
最近、送られてきたというか、
I have something that was recently sent to me.
物があって、それ見てほしいんですけど。
I'd like you to take a look at it.
これなんですよ。
This is it.
大量の••••人形。
A large amount of •••• dolls.
すごいね、執着が。
The obsession here is incredible.
いや、すごいなあ。
Wow, that's intense...
「こんなにする？」っていうくらい、
To the point of, "Why would anyone do this?"
すごい遊び方してますね...
That is a very extreme way to play with them...
これ遊びじゃなくて。
This wasn't for play.
姉妹の、妹が、姉を呪ってた。
The younger sister was cursing her older sister.
えええー！
Oh my god!
ずーっと何年も。お姉ちゃんのこと思って「死ね死ね死ね」と思って、ずっとこれを。
For years and years. She kept thinking, "Die, die, die," while doing this to the dolls.
実際、この姉妹がどうなったかというと、
And do you know what actually happened to the sisters?
姉の方が、精神病院に入院したんです。
The older sister ended up admitted to a psychiatric hospital.
はあー。
Wow...
結局、妹も精神病院に入院して、二人とも。
In the end, the younger sister was also admitted, so both of them were hospitalized.
あれとかないですか？はあとさんは、
Have you ever felt that way, Haato-san?
呪いたい相手とか、いないですか？
Is there someone you've ever wanted to curse?
だって、私が呪っちゃったら、自分も呪った分だけの対価を払わなきゃいけないから、
Because if I curse someone, I'd have to pay the price for it myself.
そこまでしてやる必要はないのかなって。
So I don't feel there's any need to go that far.
返ってくるっていうのはありますね。
Yes, the curse bouncing back is a real thing.
返ってくるんだったら嫌ですね、それは。
If it's going to bounce back to me, I definitely don't want to do it.
そしたら、クイックに呪えるやつはありますよ。
In that case, I have one that lets you curse someone quickly.
呪い教えてくれるんだｗ
You're actually teaching me how to curse people!
呪ったりするんですか？田中さん。
Do you curse people, Tanaka-san?
誰呪うんですか？ｗ
Who do you curse?!
アンチをずっと呪ってます。
I keep cursing my haters.
これは西アフリカの、呪術師が作ってくれたんですけど、
A witch doctor in West Africa made this for me.
どういう効果があるかって言ったら、
As for how it works...
これ、刺せるようになってるんですよね。
You can actually insert something into it.
で、穴が開いてて、ここにその呪いたい相手の名前を言えと。
There's a hole here, and you're supposed to speak the name of the person you want to curse into it.
名前だけで良いんだ。デスノートみたいな。
Just their name? That's like Death Note.
それで、こう、刺すと。
And then you insert this pin.
そいつに不幸が訪れる。
And misfortune will fall upon them.
ちなみに、この部屋の中で一番呪力が強い呪物ってあるんですか？
By the way, is there a cursed object with the strongest curse in this room?
いやあ...
Let's see...
こんだけ集めてると、なんか増えててもわからない場合があるんですけど、
When you collect this many, sometimes they increase in number without you realizing.
確かに。
True.
最近、これどこから、誰から貰ったのか、
Recently, I found one that I have no idea where or from whom I received it.
まったくわからへん、身に覚えがないぞっていう人形があるんですよ。
I have absolutely no memory of obtaining this doll.
ええ、見たいです。ぜひお願いします。
Oh, I'd love to see it! Yes, please.
すごい気持ち悪い人形なんですよ。
It's an incredibly creepy doll.
気持ち悪いんだｗ
Creepy, huh?
これなんですけどね。
Here it is.
ｗｗｗｗ
(Laughter)
あれ、タランちゃま...？
Wait, is that... Taran-chama?
どういう人が作ったんですかね…
What kind of person made this, I wonder...
これ…これ…
This... This is...
これ私のお姉ちゃんが作ったやつ、そうこれ
My older sister made this, yeah, this one.
はあとさんのお姉ちゃんが作ったんですか…？
Your older sister made this, Haato-san...?
え？私のお姉ちゃんが作った
Huh? My older sister made...
あの、クモのね…
...the spider one.
あ、これがね？
Ah, this one, right?
そうそう、これ体もクモになってるんですよ
Right, right. The body is also a spider.
けっこうセンスありますよね
She has quite a good sense.
お、すごいですよね、これ
Oh, isn't it amazing? This.
ぜひ置いておいてください
Please feel free to keep it here.
あっ、いいんですか？
Ah, is that okay?
じゃあ置いておこうかな…
Well, maybe I'll leave it here...
これね、呪いはない気もするけど
I feel like there's no curse on it, but...
すごい馴染んでる
It blends in so well!
でもやっぱり、なんもない人形もこういう場所に置いておけば…
But still, even an ordinary doll, if you keep it in a place like this...
え、大丈夫ですか？
Wait, is it okay?
私のお姉ちゃんが作ったんですけど、お姉ちゃん呪われちゃったりとかしません？
My older sister made it, but she won't get cursed or anything, right?
お姉ちゃんは作ってるだけなんで
Your sister only made it, so she's fine.
あ、そっか、そっか。作っただけ。わ、私…？
Ah, I see, I see. She just made it. Wait, me...?
でもね
But you know...
これほんまに…ちょっと
This is really... a bit...
あの、嫌なこと言いますけど
Um, I hate to say this, but...
え、なんですか？
Eh, what is it?
あの…
Well...
さっきから、はあとさんの後ろに、ずっと誰か居ますよね？
Since a while ago, there's been someone standing behind you, Haato-san.
あんまし言いたくなかったんですけど
I didn't really want to say it, but...
ずっと誰か憑いてきてますよ
Someone has been following you the whole time.
え…？
Eh...?
また追っかけた ちょっと考えた 馬鹿な女のままで良かった
I chased after you again, I thought about it a bit. It was fine being a stupid woman.
だからどうした 自ら望んだと
So what? Didn't you say you wanted this...
言ってんじゃん
...yourself?
また追っかけた ちょっと考えた
I chased after you again, I thought about it a bit.
少々ちょっと考えた
I thought about it just a tiny bit.
だからどうした
So what?
お望み通りの 末路です
It's just as you wished, it's our end.
なんで なんでなんでなんでなんでなんでなんで
Why? Why, why, why, why, why, why, why?
なの？どうあがいても無理
Is it? No matter what we do, it's impossible.
なんで なんでなんでなんで
Why? Why, why, why, why?
なんだ、そんなもんか
What, is that all it is?
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いない
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. I'm sure it is, no doubt about it.
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 絶対に
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. I'm sure it is, absolutely.
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いない
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. I'm sure it is, no doubt about it.
まぁそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いないの
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. I'm sure it is, there's no mistake.
違いないよ絶対
There's no mistake, absolutely.
また追っかけた ちょっと躊躇った
I chased after you again, I hesitated a bit.
確かに躊躇った
I certainly hesitated.
なんだかなぁ なんだかなぁ そういうことではない
I don't know, I don't know... That's not what this is about.
また追っかけた ちょっと躊躇った
I chased after you again, I hesitated a bit.
なんだなんだなんだなんだ あなた
What, what, what, what are you?
だからだからこんなことは
That's why, that's why, this kind of thing...
望んでないから
...is not what I wanted.
なんで なんでなんでなんでなんでなんでなんで
Why? Why, why, why, why, why, why, why?
なの？どうあがいても無理
Is it? No matter what we do, it's impossible.
なんで なんでなんでなんで
Why? Why, why, why, why?
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従って
Obey, obey, obey me.
君に一切の拒否権ないよ
You have absolutely no right to refuse.
黙って従って
Shut up and obey.
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従って
Obey, obey, obey me.
お願いお願いお願いお願い
Please, please, please, please...
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従って
Obey, obey, obey me.
従え 従って って言ってんの
Obey, obey, I'm telling you!
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従って
Obey, obey, obey me.
お願いお願いお願いお願いお願い…
Please, please, please, please...
お願い
Please.
ということで、サロメちゃんに来てもらったよ！
And with that, Salome-chan is here with us!
1、10、100、1000、満点サロメ！
1, 10, 100, 1000, Manten Salome!
皆様方を100万点笑顔にさせますわ！
I shall put a 1,000,000-point smile on all of your faces!
今はまだ一般人、いつかお嬢様になりたい！そして今日は…
Right now I'm just an ordinary person, but I hope to be a lady one day! And today...
はあと様をお祝いに来ました！100万点バラサロメでございますわ！
...I came to celebrate with Haato-sama! I am Hyakumantenbara Salome!
はあと様ー！
Haato-sama!
サロメちゃん！来てくれてありがとう！
Salome-chan! Thank you so much for coming!
ド屑一緒に歌えて凄く嬉しい！
I'm so happy we got to sing "Do Kuzu" together!
歌ってみたも本当に最高でしたわ！
The cover song was absolutely fantastic as well!
普段お上品なサロメちゃんの、ヤンデレ感が堪りませんでした！
Your usual elegant self showing that yandere vibe was just irresistible!
歌声も喋り方も性格も
Your singing voice, your way of speaking, your personality...
好きです！
...I love them all!
はあと様、本当にありがとうございますわ！
Haato-sama, thank you so very much!
こちらこそ！
The pleasure is all mine!
なんかこうやって、あの、縁が繋がって、
To think that somehow we connected like this,
こうやって今、一緒に歌を歌えたのが凄く嬉しいですわ。
and are now able to sing together, makes me so incredibly happy.
もう凄い、もう私、はあと様の事も全部可愛いと思ってるし本当に、
Seriously, I find everything about you so cute, Haato-sama, truly!
可愛い！
So cute!
おめでとう、今日は本当にありがとうございました、はあと様。
Congratulations, and thank you so much for today, Haato-sama.
こちらこそありがとう！
Thank you too!
さようなら、まったねー！
Goodbye, see you again!
またねー！
See you again!
約束しに参上仕ったが主人様
"I have arrived to fulfill my promise, Master."
隣に座って
Sit down next to me.
せーの 萌え 萌え 萌え 萌え
One, two, moe, moe, moe, moe!
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who on earth would be pleased by this?
ねぇ教えて、え？
Hey, tell me, eh?
笑顔でアップアップ
Smile and up, up!
愛想忘れてご苦労様
Thanks for working hard without any amiability.
私とあなたでせーの、らぶらぶらぶらぶ
You and I, on three... love, love, love, love!
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ、ねえ教えて？
Who would be happy with this? Hey, tell me.
笑顔でアップアップ
Smile and up, up!
ひらりひらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering, a girl...
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, lies of words...
それってつまりおさめな子
In other words, a childish girl.
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップアップ
An emotional reality, smile and up, up!
人は見かけによらぬもの
People aren't what they seem.
噂は嘘だと見抜けない
You can't see through the rumors as lies.
知ったか顔 その場しのぎ
A know-it-all face, just getting by.
鳥肌 鮫肌 And more
Goosebumps, shark skin, and more.
間違えた子 指名を頂きます
The girl who made a mistake, I'll take her nomination.
私とあなたでせーの、らぶらぶらぶらぶ
You and I, on three... love, love, love, love!
これはお派手にご苦労様
Well, thanks for your hard work in such a flashy way.
遊びましょう 笑顔でアップアップ
Let's play, smile and up, up!
ひらりひらり 此処は何処
Fluttering, fluttering, where is this?
ふわりフわり 底冷えの衝
Softly, softly, a chilling urge...
それってつまりおさめな子
In other words, a childish girl.
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップアップ
An emotional reality, smile and up, up!
奪いだす 秘密の鍵
Stealing away the secret key...
終わることのない この世界
...of this never-ending world.
悲しい子は
The sad children...
寂しい子は
...the lonely children...
眠らせて
...let them sleep.
おままごと 遊びましょう 笑顔でアップアップ
Let's play house, smile and up, up!
ひらりひらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering, a girl...
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, lies of words...
それってつまりおさめな子
In other words, a childish girl.
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップアップ
An emotional reality, smile and up, up!
遊びましょう 笑顔でアップアップ
Let's play, smile and up, up!
アップアップ
Up, up!
はーちゃま！
Haachama!
わー！お誕生日おめでとう！
Yay! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！来てくれて！
Thank you for coming!
なんとね、2021年の...
Believe it or not, since 2021...
...4年ぶりに来てくれました！
...she's come here for the first time in 4 years!
チュウリングラブ歌ったの覚えてる？
Do you remember singing 'Churing Love'?
覚えてる！4年前に！お誕生日おめでとうって。
I remember! 4 years ago! Wishing you a happy birthday.
ね、若かったよね。
We were so young back then, right?
え、今はなんか違う？若くない？
Wait, are we different now? Not young?
今はでもクールになったんだよね。
Well, we've become cool now.
我々今日もクール可愛かったもんね。
We were cool and cute today too, right?
確かにね。
Indeed.
いつもならチュウリングラブでこんなことしてたよね。
Usually we would do something like this for 'Churing Love', right?
なんかあの、ヲタ芸とかしてたから。
Since we were doing wotagei dancing and stuff.
チュウリングラブだったけど、だいぶクールになりました。
It was 'Churing Love', but we've become quite cool now.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
ちょっと近すぎるだろ。
You're a bit too close!
近っ！
So close!
え、わかんないよ。
Wait, I don't know.
写真とか...そうね、今日歌ったモエチャッカファイアね。
Photos and... oh right, 'Moe Chackka Fire' which we sang today.
歌ってみたも出したので、ぜひ見てください。
We also released a cover version, so please check it out!
なんでこの曲にしてくれたんですか？
Why did you choose this song?
ええ、これ歌いたかった！
Oh, I really wanted to sing this!
やっぱね、歌ってみたも出したし、生誕でも一緒に歌いたいなと思って、選びました。
After all, we released a cover, and I wanted to sing it together on my birthday, so I chose it.
おお、なんか意外な選曲だった、これ。
Oh, that was a pretty unexpected song choice.
え、本当に？なんかこれ、今回ホラーライブがテーマなんだけど。
Really? Well, the theme this time is 'Horror Live'.
そんなコンセプトのライブ見たことない！
I've never seen a live show with such a concept!
いや、なんか、ちょっと、合うかなと思って。
No, I just thought it might fit well.
あ、なるほどね。ちょっとね、落ち着いてね。
Ah, I see. Let's calm down a bit.
なんか、一緒に写真とか撮る？
Shall we take some photos together?
撮る！撮りたい！
Yes! I want to take some!
てかすごい、マジで。ライブステージ。
By the way, this is amazing, seriously. The live stage.
ね、めっちゃ可愛い。
Right? It's super cute.
え、なんか、いいポーズ。やりたいポーズとかある？
Is there a good pose? Any pose you want to do?
え、まず、まず普通。普通ね。
First, first a normal one. Just normal, right?
イェーイ！
Yay!
パシャ。
*Snap*
え、可愛い。
Aw, cute.
パシャ、パシャ。
*Snap, snap*
え、すごい、いいの撮れたでしょ。
Wow, we got a really good one, didn't we?
あと、あとは？ハート。
What else? Heart?
ハート？ハート？ハートしとく？
Heart? Heart? Should we do a heart?
できてる？
Are we doing it?
いい感じ！
Looking good!
いい感じ！よし！
Looking good! Alright!
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
あとは？
What else?
えー、あと何だろう？なんかでかくね？
Hmm, what else? Something big?
あ、これ、これ、これ、これ。
Oh, this, this, this, this.
やだー！
Oh, no!
うわー！
Whoa!
って、感じね。
...something like that.
あれは、4年前にもさ、撮ったさ、なんかちょっと座って、エモエモなみたいなの。
What about that emotional one we took 4 years ago, where we sat down a bit?
こっちじゃない？こっちじゃない？
Isn't it this way? This way?
みんなの方向いてね。
Face everyone.
うーん...
Hmm...
あ、いい！いい！いいじゃん！
Oh, nice! Nice! Looks great!
4年前もこれで撮ったんだよ。
We took a photo like this 4 years ago too.
イェーイ！みんな見てる？
Yay! Is everyone watching?
イェーイ！
Yay!
久しぶりの、はっちゃま。
Haachama after such a long time.
衣装も変わってね。
And with different outfits.
イェーイ！
Yay!
ねえ、これ結構隠してるけど...
Hey, you're hiding them quite a bit, but...
この足よ！
look at these legs!
違う、隠してるのが逆にいいんだって！
No, hiding them actually makes it better!
あ、そっち？チラ見えのね。
Ah, that way? Just a glimpse?
分かってる、分かってる。
You get it, you get it.
この、あれだもんね。
It's like that, right?
やばい、絵面やばい。
Oh my, this camera angle is crazy!
ライブの絵面じゃなかったよ。
That was definitely not a live concert shot!
絶対領域がね。
The absolute territory, right?
よーし。
Alright...
どう？なんかセクシーポーズとかしなくて大丈夫？
How is it? Do we need to do a sexy pose or something?
セクシーポーズ？
Sexy pose?
したいの？
Do you want to do one?
大丈夫かな？いや、大丈夫です！...
Is that okay? No, actually, I'm good!
おめでとう、誕生日！
Happy birthday!
あ、ありがとう！
Ah, thank you!
またなんか、一緒に歌って踊りたい！
I want to sing and dance with you again!
うん、うん、踊ろう、ぜひ！
Yeah, let's dance, absolutely!
ぜひともまた次も踊りましょう！
Let's definitely dance together next time too!
歌いましょう！
And sing too!
じゃあ、バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！頑張ってね！
Bye-bye! Good luck!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
正しくなれない霧が どこを観た
A fog that cannot be right, where did it look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
I wanted to check everything, one by one.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた僕らは
I want to keep thinking; we who met through lies,
何ひとつも 奪われてないから
have not had a single thing stolen from us.
正しくなれない
作詞・作曲 : ACAね
Can't Be Right
Written & Composed by ACAne
僕ら 育っていくみたい
It seems like we are growing up,
愛されるみたい あたたかな波を読む
like we are being loved, reading the warm waves.
変わる 今を選ぶ
Choosing the changing present,
澄んだ 朝色 尋ねる声で何度も
with a voice that asks for the clear morning color again and again.
僕ら 嘘つきだね
We are liars, aren't we?
両想いだね
Our feelings are mutual.
枯れ果てるまで泣き笑い 今日を
Crying and laughing until we completely wither, today...
受け入れていく
...we will accept it.
喜びあった日々を忘れはしないけど
Though I won't forget the days we rejoiced together...
知らないほうが幸せだって
They say ignorance is bliss,
知れば
but if you know,
知り得るほど
the more you come to know...
正しくなれない霧が どこを観た
A fog that cannot be right, where did it look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
I wanted to check everything, one by one.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた僕らは
I want to keep thinking; we who met through lies,
何ひとつも 奪われてないから
have not had a single thing stolen from us.
今 心 閉ざさないように
So as not to close off my heart right now,
虎視眈々と 暮れを続けよう 枯れ木に笑顔だけ
I'll vigilantly watch as the day ends, leaving only smiles on withered trees.
君の肉体 奉仕 全て
Your physical body, service, everything,
無駄になんてさせないよ
I won't let any of it go to waste.
ねえ 知り得る
Hey, what you can know
ほうが幸せだって
is supposedly happier,
辿り着いてもいい？
is it okay if I reach that point?
君だけが視る 夕焼けが陰って鏡
The sunset only you see cast in shadow, a mirror...
僕でも いつか 分かる日まで
...until the day even I can understand it.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた
I want to keep thinking; if it's a script...
シナリオなら 分かるよ
...where we met through lies, I would understand...
導かれ
...being guided.
大したもんじゃない 無駄なもんじゃない
It's nothing special, but it's not useless either.
幸せの輪を 寛大にしていけるように
So that we can generously expand the circle of happiness...
ずっと
...forever.
もうずっと 茶化されようが 折れない
Even if we're made fun of forever, we won't break...
素直なまま 可能性が
...remaining honest, the possibility...
見逃せるならば 可能性を
If we can afford to overlook it, the possibility...
諦められないから まだ
...is something I cannot give up on yet.
正しくなれない霧が どこを観た
A fog that cannot be right, where did it look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
I wanted to check everything, one by one.
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた僕らは
I want to keep thinking; we who met through lies,
何ひとつも
have not...
すべて 嫌われても
...even if we are completely hated,
奪われてないから
...had a single thing stolen from us.
はあとちゃん！
Haato-chan!
大好きだよ、ちゅっ
I love you, *kiss*
はあとも！
Haato too!
はあとも、私も大好き！
Haato too! I love you too!
ごめん
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry...
いなくなって寂しかったよ
I was so lonely when you were gone...
いつも側にいるって言ったじゃん
But you said you'd always be by my side!
ずっと待ってたよ
I've been waiting for you all this time...
ちゃま？ちゃま？
Chama? Chama?
はーちゃま！はーちゃま！ちゃまだよ！
Haachama! Haachama! It's Chama!
こうやって対話するのは、初めてだよね！
This is our first time talking to each other like this!
さっき歌ってた感触、最高だったよ！
The feeling of singing just now was the absolute best!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんか大人っぽくなったね？
You've become somewhat more mature, haven't you?
実は、最近旅をすることが増えまして、
Actually, I've been traveling more lately,
そこで新しい自分を見つけて、
and I found a new side of myself there,
ちょっぴり大人っぽい曲にチャレンジしてみました！
so I decided to challenge myself with a slightly more mature song!
おお！特に好きな歌詞とかはある？
Oh! Are there any lyrics you especially like?
はい！「もう一度、もう一度と何度思ったでしょう」という歌詞がありまして、
Yes! There's a lyric that goes, "How many times did I think, 'Just once more, just once more'..."
出会った景色や人の温もりを思いながら、凄く感情移入しました。
I really poured my emotions into it while thinking of the scenery and warmth of the people I met.
おお、そうなんだ！
Oh, is that so!
今日リリース予定なのでみんなもたくさん聴いてね！
It's scheduled to be released today, so please listen to it a lot, everyone!
ぜひぜひ！
Definitely, definitely!
デュエットで「正しくなれない」歌ったよ！どうだった？
We sang "Tadashiku Narenai" as a duet! How was it?
今までの記憶とか葛藤を振り返りながらだね、凄く心に染みましたね。
Reflecting on our memories and struggles up until now, it really touched my heart.
本当だよ！
That's so true!
ハートちゃんはさ、ずっと塞ぎ込んで、全然はーちゃんのこと見向きもしないんだもん。
You were feeling down for so long, Haato-chan, and you didn't look at Haachama at all.
そんなことないけど…ごめんね。
That's not true, but... I'm sorry.
demo, otagai shiriatte wakariaeta kara, yokatta natte omou yo.
But I'm really glad we got to know and understand each other.
おお、ならいっか！
Oh, then it's all good!
そんな二人の家族写真を今回は撮ってもらいました！
This time, we had a family photo of the two of us taken!
イェーイ！
Yay!
二人の仲良しの証！
Proof of our close friendship!
はい！B2タペストリーになっております！
Yes! It's available as a B2 tapestry!
おしゃれだ！はーちゃま行くよ！
So stylish! Haachama, here we go!
うん！せーの！
Yeah! One, two...
みんな、グッズ！
Everyone, the merch!
ゲットしてください！
Please get yours!
ねえ見て お気に入りの
Hey, look at my favorite,
世界に一つの お人形さん
one-of-a-kind doll in the world.
顔も性格も 違ったけど
Though our faces and personalities differed,
ずっとみんな なかよし
we've always been close friends.
「苦しい」を救いあったとき
When we saved each other from pain,
私にもできた恩返し
I was finally able to return the favor.
大事な人、好きな人
Precious people, beloved people,
いつもそばにいてほしい、よね。
I want them to always be by my side, right?
上手に縫ってね
Sew me up nicely, okay?
私にしてくれたように
Just like you did for me.
少しほつれたとことか
Even the parts that have frayed a little...
めちゃ可愛いね
...are super cute, right?
身体もたくさん
Stitch together lots of body parts, too,
好きに繋ぎ合わせて
just the way you like.
少し歪だけどね
Even if it's a bit distorted,
大切な家族たちなの
they're still my precious family.
ねえ見て お気に入りの
Hey, look at my favorite,
世界に一つの お人形さん
one-of-a-kind doll in the world.
かおもせいかくも ちがったけど
Though our faces and personalities differed,
ずっとみんな なかよし
we've always been close friends.
なかよし なかよし なかよし なかよし なかよし
Close friends, close friends, close friends, close friends, close friends...
やさしい、うれしい、たのしい、いとしい
Kind, happy, fun, beloved.
ほめて、なでて
Praise me, pet me,
ねえ、ねえ
hey, hey...
Hey, hey,
ねえ、ねえ！
hey, hey!
上手に縫ってね
Sew me up nicely, okay?
私にしてくれたように
Just like you did for me.
少し解れたとことか
Even the parts that have frayed a little...
めちゃ可愛いね
...are super cute, right?
身体もたくさん
Stitch together lots of body parts, too,
好きに繋ぎ合わせて
just the way you like.
少し歪だけどね。
Even if it's a bit distorted,
大切な。
My precious...
...precious...
たいせつな。
家族たちの
Our family's...
生誕ライブ限定 グッズ販売のお知らせ！
An announcement for limited-edition birthday live merch!
家族写真B2タペストリー！
Family Photo B2 Tapestry!
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと
Featuring a gorgeous frame-like design...
肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート！
...the portrait-like duo is incredibly cute!
お部屋の壁に 今日の思い出を飾って
Decorate your room's wall with today's memories...
彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます！
...and enjoy a vibrant life supporting your favorite idol!
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ！
Outing-Chama Plushie!
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ！
An incredibly adorable plushie with button-like eyes!
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと
Featuring Chama in her dress outfit, meticulously recreated...
一緒にお出かけして旅に出られちゃいます！
...you can go out and travel together!
鞄に付けられるハートチャーム付き！
Comes with a heart charm to attach to your bag!
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ！
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch!
あの...タランちゃまがポーチに！？
That Taran-Chama is... now a pouch?!
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム！
A handy item with a zipper on her back for storage!
ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる！
Taran-Chama in her Gothic Lolita outfit is just too cute!
チェーンがついているから安心して お外にお散歩させられるよ！
She has a chain, so you can safely take her on walks!
タランちゃまスマホリング！
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring!
スマホの落下はタランちゃまにお任せ！
Leave protecting your phone from drops to Taran-Chama!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます！
She will stick on tight and protect it!
愛くるしいお目目とつい目が合っちゃう瞬間も
Even those moments where you lock eyes with those adorable eyes...
癒されてたまりません！
...will soothe you beyond belief!
フルセットは数量限定もあります！
The full set is also available in limited quantities!
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは
The limited-edition version of the full-set purchase bonus...
箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと
...includes a foil-stamped postcard with a printed message,
赤井はあと直筆サイン！
and a hand-signed autograph by Akai Haato!
特典ボイス「ひみつのはなし」もあるよ！
There's also a bonus voice drama, "A Secret Story"!
トレカもあるよ！
There's also a trading card!
hololive公式ECサイトで販売中！
Now on sale at the official hololive online shop!